Hochstr. 40

90429 Nürnberg Mobile: +49 176 82098294

E-mail: oz@tiram.it WWW: oz123.github.io

Solving interesting problems, isn't about only finding the best algorithm, or choosing the right tool. Software is made for computers, but it needs to be understood by people. By people we should not just consider developers. Good software projects are made with awesome tools. Great software project are made by great teams. My experience through the years has thought me that no buzz word or new fancy technology can replace good team work. DevOps and Agile, done right, are great frameworks to enable great team work."

### PROFESSIONAL EXPERIENCE

#### Senior IT Architect & Lead Developer noris network ag

March 2018 - Current

- In-house and customer facing consultant for cloud native technologies.
- Plan and Deploy Kubernetes\Openshift clusters on OpenStack\vSphere
- Lead distributed development teams
- Lead Developmer of in house Kubernetes distribution
- Certified Kubernetes Adminstrator
- Initiate and Organize Kubenrentes CNCF official meetup for the region

 Kubernetes
 Openshift
 OpenStack
 Python
 Docker
 Ansible
 gitlab
 Go-lang

## **Lead Developer** The Mobility House GmbH

August 2016 - February 2018

- Write Jenkins CI\CD pipelines
- Plan and Deploy Kubernetes clusters on AWS
- Build Infrastructure with SaltStack, Docker, AWS
- Develop Micro-Services using Python, Go and RabbitMQ
- Interview and hire developers
- Mentor Junior Developers

Kubernetes AWS Python Pandas SaltStack Packer Docker Terraform git Go-lang

### Lead DevOps + Data Engineer Plan-Net GmbH

August 2014 - August 2016

- Lead migration from Subversion to Git
- Develop ETL jobs in python python-pandas and multiple other python libraries.
- Develop extraction jobs from MongoDB to tableau using C and Python APIs.
- Maintain a cluster of multiple mongodb replication and shard nodes.
- Maintain all Linux hosts with salt-stack, network architecture plan and execution. Deploy all hosts, maintain firewalls, openvpn, and everything needed to guarantee continuous rolling of ETL jobs needed for the daily business.
- Implement web interfaces for reporting using python-flask and javascript.

MongoDB Python Pandas NoSQL Tableau OpenVZ flask saltstack ipython git big-data

Backend development of a high traffic E-Mail marketing SaaS.

- Develop internal tools using flask and sqlalchemy automate work flows.
- Extend continuous integration and introduce automated Selenium driven testing.
- Standardization of code packages, setuptools, coverage.py, code analysis & review.
- Manage work flows with Jira.
- Write sphinx documentation for python libraries developed in-house



## Software Engineer, System Engineer Science+Computing AG

January 2011 - January 2014

My tasks as Software Engineer were:

- Develop different custom software solution for internal customers and external customers.
- Develop eclipse plug-ins that are part of OpenMDM project.
- Develop a Django front end for managing multiple user accounts in LDAP and Active Directory.
- Implement back-end scripts to synchronize AD user accounts and LDAP accounts.
- Setup and configure OpenLDAP.
- Work on multiple Django projects.
- Contribute to PDMCAE (Data management software in BMW written in C, C++, Perl, Pl\SQL)



My tasks as System Engineer were:

- Install and Configure Windows and Linux (Red Hat 5,6 and CentOS) Workstations.
- Install and Configure HPC Clusters.
- Scripting: BASH, Python and Perl.
- Backup tool: TSM Client\Server support (On Windows and Linux).
- Hardware and Software RAID configuration.
- Monitoring (Nagios\RRDtool) Queuing systems (Sun Grid Engine\In house queuing system).
- Windows\Linux sharing (CIFS & SAMBA).
- 2nd level support for Engineers using CAE\CAD software.
- Install and configure MySQL databases.
- Install and configure SAN such as AutoFS, AMD and Windows DFS.
- Maintain LDAP servers.
- Actively responsible for packaging software in RPM, DEB and other packaging format.
- Responsible for as much as 5000 computers (Workstations and cluster nodes) for renowned customers such Daimler, Porsche and BMW.



#### **Scientific Programmer** *Uni. British Columbia, Vancouver.*

May, 2010 - Oct., 2010

- Implement a sequential version of a reactive transport model (Ground water flow + Chemical reactions) using an existing large and complex Fortran code.
- Write a collection of Python scripts: to submit jobs on different cluster hosts with different input files, to process the results and visualize them.
- The results of the code work and benchmarking comparing to previous versions were submitted as M.Sc thesis.

Fortran95 Makefile GCC Python LATEX

## **System Administrator, Python Programmer**

Uni. Tübingen, Germany

Oct. 2008 - April 2010

- Install and configure home brewed 2 Debian clusters with 20 compute nodes.
- Setup Subversion & Trac servers.
- Implement Python application to process GIS data and visualize the results (see blow MMSPy).
- Maintain firewalls to the Clusters and the TRAC server.

 Debian
 Trac
 Subversion
 Python
 GDAL
 GIS
 IPTables
 PfSense

## System Administrator Rankabove, Israel

April, 2008 - August, 2008

- Configuration management of Windows, OSX desktops and Ubuntu\Debian Servers.
- Install and maintain Bugzilla for our clients.
- Package software (DEB format) for deployment.

Debian Packaging Bugzilla Ubuntu Shell Python OSX Windows

#### **EDUCATION**

M. Sc. Applied Env. Geosciences Universität Tübingen, Germany

October 2008 - October 2010

#### **Thesis Title:**

Implementation of Sequential Non Iterative approach in MIN3P reactive transport code and comparison of Global Implicit Method, final GPA 1.6.

**B.Sc. Geology** Hebrew University, Jerusalem

October, 2003 - March, 2008

B.Sc. Final GPA 88/100.

#### RECENT OPEN SOURCE PROJECTS & CONTRIBUTIONS

I contribute to numerous open source projects in various forms. Recent examples are:

- Kubernetes documentation, Python Client
- Submitting patches to Python's STL, SaltStack
- Maintain Gentoo ebuilds
- Report and triage bugs in multiple applications I use

The list is too long to include all here. Check my github.com/oz123

#### PUBLIC SPEAKING AND WORKSHOPS

- Advanced Python workshop, PloneConf, Boston, 2016.
- Building a WSGI framework, PloneConf, Barcelona, 2017.
- Secure Continuous Delivery in Kubernets Clusters ,DevOps Days, Berlin, 2018.
- Advanced Flow Control in Python, Python Summit, Berlin, 2018.

### LANGUAGE SKILLS

Mother language: Hebrew.

Other languages*:	Understanding		Speaking	Writing
	Listening	Reading		
English	C2	C2	C2	C2
German	C2	C2	C2	C2
* Evaluation according to Common European Framework of Reference (CEF).				

#### **DRIVING LICENSE**

PKW, Private Auto, Class B.

### **WORK PERMIT**

German Citizen

Eligible to work and live in EU\Canada.

### **SKILLS MATRIX**

Level of skill:

- 6. I could write a book about it.
- 5. Used in multiple projects, contributed bug reports, submitted patches.
- 4. Have done more than 3 projects, involving more than 8000 line of code.
- 3. Used in production, worked on a few small scale projects.
- 2. Have done single small scale project, used it occasionally.
- 1. Took a course in the university, read a single book.

## **Scripting\Dynamic Languages**

Language	Skill Level
Python	6
BASH	4
JavaScript	4

## **Compiled Languages**

JAVA	4
С	3
Go	3
C++	2
Fortran	2
Pascal	1

## Markup & Web

LATEX	5
HTML	3
CSS	2
MARKDOWN	5
Sphinx\reStructuredText	5

# **Operating Systems**

RHEL	5
Debian	5
SuSE	4
Windows	3
Gentoo	5
FreeBSD	2
OS X	2

# **Python Frameworks & Development tools**

Django	4
Flask\Bottle	5
Selenium	2
Git	5
Make	4

## **Databases**

MongoDB	4
MySQL	3
SQLite	4
PostgreSQL	3
Oracle	1

# **DevOps tools**

Kubernetes	5
SaltStack	5
Docker	4
Docker-compose	2
AWS	4
OpenStack	5
Packer	3
Ansible	3
Terraform	3
vagrant	4
Gitlab CI	4